Guide to the Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York Records 1785-2014 MS 2997
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: Administrative Records, 1785-2008
  - Subseries I.5: Constitution, Rules, and History, 1842-2008
    - Historical sketch of the Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York, with the constitution & a list of officers & members since 1756: Centennial oration, before the Society, on the 1st December, 1856 (Offsite-box SA-8, Volume 50)
    - Constitution of the Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York, as proposed to be amended at the preparatory meeting, on 14th November, 1867 (Offsite-box SA-8, Volume 51)
    - The Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York: constitution and act of incorporation: historical sketch: list of officers and members since 1756., 1868 (Offsite-box SA-8, Volume 52)
    - Record book: containing the act of incorporation, constitution, historical sketch and centennial oration, with a list of officers and members since 1756 and at the present time, 1895 (Offsite-box SA-8, Volume 53)
    - History of the Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York, 1756 - 1906 (Offsite-box SA-8, Volume 54)
    - Rules, &c. of the St. Andrew's Society at New York, in the province of New York. Adopted November 30th, 1764; with list of members, resident and honorary, for the year 1770., 1915 (Offsite-box SA-8, Volume 55)
    - Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York: amendments to the constitution, 1945 (Offsite-box SA-8, Volume 56)
    - Two hundredth anniversary, 1756-1956, of Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York (Offsite-box SA-8, Volume 57)
    - Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York: constitution as amended to November 30, 1973 (Offsite-box SA-8, Volume 58)
    - Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York: constitution as amended to May 6, 1982 (Offsite-box SA-8, Volume 59)
    - Two hundred fifty years, 1756-2006: the history of Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York, 2008 (Offsite-box SA-8, Volume 60)
    - Duplicate organizational publications, 1857 - 1982 (Offsite-box 97)
  - Subseries I.6: Governance Committee Records, 1939-1989
    Governance Committee Records primarily document the process of selecting members to lead and administer the work of the organization. The Nominating Committee selected officers, chaplains, physicians, and members of the Banquet Committee. The Standing Committee appointed a Finance Committee and attended to other executive business. The subseries contains correspondence, meeting minutes, lists of candidates, and related material.
    Nominating Committee records are arranged first, followed by the records of the Standing Committee. Each set is ordered chronologically.
    - Nominating Committee, 1939 - 1947 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 9)
    - Nominating Committee, 1948 - 1949 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 10)
    - Nominating Committee, 1950 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 11)
    - Nominating Committee, 1951 - 1952 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 12)
    - Nominating Committee, 1953 - 1954 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 13)
    - Nominating Committee, 1955 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 14)
    - Nominating Committee, 1956 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 15)
    - Nominating Committee, 1957 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 1)
    - Nominating Committee, 1958 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 2)
    - Nominating Committee, 1959 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 3)
    - Nominating Committee, 1960 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 4)
    - Nominating Committee, 1961 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 5)
    - Nominating Committee, 1962 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 6)
    - Nominating Committee, 1963 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 7)
    - Nominating Committee, 1964 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 8)
    - Nominating Committee, 1965 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 9)
    - Nominating Committee, 1966 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 10)
    - Nominating Committee, 1968 - 1969 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 11)
    - Nominating Committee, 1970 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 12)
    - Nominating Committee, 1971 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 1)
    - Nominating Committee, 1972 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 2)
    - Nominating Committee, 1973 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 3)
    - Nominating Committee, 1974 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 4)
    - Nominating Committee, 1975 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 5)
    - Nominating Committee, 1976 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 6)
    - Nominating Committee, 1977 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 7)
    - Nominating Committee, 1978 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 8)
    - Nominating Committee, 1979 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 9)
    - Nominating Committee, 1980 - 1981 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 10)
    - Nominating Committee, 1982 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 11)
    - Nominating Committee, 1983 - 1984 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 12)
    - Nominating Committee, 1985 - 1986 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 13)
    - Nominating Committee, 1987 - 1989 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 14)
    - Standing Committee, 1960, 1963 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 1)
    - Standing Committee, 1964 - 1967 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 2)
    - Standing Committee, 1970 February - April (Offsite-box 16, Folder 3)
    - Standing Committee, 1970 June - October (Offsite-box 16, Folder 4)
    - Standing Committee, 1971, 1973, 1975 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 5)
    - Standing Committee, 1978 - 1979 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 6)
    - Standing Committee, 1981 - 1982 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 7)
    - Standing Committee, 1983 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 8)
    - Standing Committee, 1985 - 1987, 1989 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 9)
  - Subseries I.7: General Files of the Recording Secretary, 1933-circa 1991
    General files held by the Recording Secretary document the routine administrative affairs of the Society. Correspondence frequently involves presidents and other officers in the organization. Material is arranged chronologically.
    - Correspondence, Scottish Organizations, 1933 - 1966 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 10)
    - Members in the Services, 1942 - 1944 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 11)
    - Questionnaire on War Affairs: Civilians, 1944 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 12)
    - Questionnaire on War Affairs: Members Serving, 1944 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 13)
    - Questionnaire on War Affairs: Members' Sons, 1944 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 1)
    - Constitution and Amendments, 1945, 1950, 1978 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 2)
    - Committee Assignments, 1947 - 1948 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 3)
    - CARE, 1947 - 1949 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 4)
    - Greetings, 1948 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Reginald Stewart, 1949 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 6)
    - Greetings, 1949 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 7)
    - Greetings, 1950 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, James A. Keillor, 1952 - 1953 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, John M. MacGregor, 1954 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 10)
    - Bicentennial Correspondence, John M. MacGregor, 1955 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 11)
    - Bicentennial Exhibition, 1955 - 1956 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 12)
    - Morgan Library Exhibition, 1956 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 1)
    - 200th Anniversary Appropriations & Membership Committee, 1956 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence, 1956 - 1957 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, Thomas P. Haig, 1956 - 1958 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, Godfrey Macdonald, 1957 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, David B. McVean, 1957 - 1959 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 6)
    - History Book Orders and Promotion, 1957 - 1960 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, David Baillie Morrison, 1957 - 1961 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 8)
    - Year Book, 1957, 1958, 1962, 1963 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 9)
    - General Correspondence, 1958 January - April (Offsite-box 18, Folder 10)
    - General Correspondence, 1958 May (Offsite-box 18, Folder 11)
    - General Correspondence, 1958 June-August (Offsite-box 18, Folder 12)
    - General Correspondence, 1958 September - December (Offsite-box 19, Folder 1)
    - James Forgie Memorial Fund, 1958 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 2)
    - Lord Advocate Luncheon, 1958 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, Allan C. George, 1958 - 1959, 1963 - 1964 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 4)
    - General Correspondence, 1959 January - April (Offsite-box 19, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence, 1959 May - August (Offsite-box 19, Folder 6)
    - General Correspondence, 1959 September - December (Offsite-box 19, Folder 7)
    - General Correspondence, 1960 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, Hugh S. MacLean, 1960 - 1961 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 9)
    - Treasurer's Reports and Financial Statement, 1960 - 1961, 1969 - 1975, 1982 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence, 1961 January - March (Offsite-box 20, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence, 1961 April - August (Offsite-box 20, Folder 3)
    - General Correspondence, 1961 September - December (Offsite-box 20, Folder 4)
    - History Book Orders, 1962 - 1965 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence, 1962 January - February (Offsite-box 20, Folder 6)
    - General Correspondence, 1962 March - June (Offsite-box 21, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence, 1962 July - October (Offsite-box 21, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence, 1962 November - 1963 February (Offsite-box 21, Folder 3)
    - General Correspondence, 1963 March - April (Offsite-box 21, Folder 4)
    - General Correspondence, 1963 May - September (Offsite-box 21, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence, 1963 October - December (Offsite-box 21, Folder 6)
    - General Correspondence, 1964 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Henry J. Cochran Jr., 1964 - 1965 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence, 1965 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 3)
    - General Correspondence, 1966 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 4)
    - Legislation, 1966 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Everett M. Clark, 1966 - 1967 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, Everett M. Clark, 1966 - 1968 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, Nestor J. MacDonald, 1968 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 8)
    - Neighborhood Thrift Shop, 1968 - 1971 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Donald Gregg, 1971 - 1972 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 10)
    - Kenneth C. MacPherson Estate, 1972 - 1977 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 11)
    - General File re: Saint Andrew's Day, the admission of women as members, 1972 - 1980 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, Dr. Gordon L. Barclay, 1975 - 1977 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 13)
    - General Correspondence, 1976 - 1980 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 14)
    - Ward Melville Bequest, 1977 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 1)
    - Recording Secretary Duties and Proceedures, 1977 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 2)
    - Recording Secretary's Reports, 1977 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 3)
    - Honorary Member Certificates, Ian W. McDonald, 1977 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 4)
    - Member Notes, 1977 - 1980 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Dougald L. MacLean, 1977 - 1978 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 6)
    - Ralph A. Kennedy Estate, 1978 - 1979 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 8)
    - Alexander Hamilton Estate, 1979 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 8)
    - Membership Procedures, 1979 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 9)
    - Publicity Committee, 1979 - 1980 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 10)
    - General Correspondence and Greetings, Robert Coe, 1982 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 11)
    - General Correspondence, 1982 - 1983 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 12)
    - Minutes and statements, 1982 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 13)
    - "The Pride of the Clyde Celebrations" promotional material, 1983 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, Gracie Mansion Conservancy, 1988 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 15)
    - George Washington Inauguration Bicentennial, 1989 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 16)
    - Cypress Hills Cemetery correspondence with photocopies of material ca. 1920 - 1950, ca. 1991 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 17)
- Series II: Charitable Records (RESTRICTIONS APPLY), 1802-1992
  Charitable records document the Society's mission to provide aid to individuals of Scottish descent. Responsibility for the dispersal of aid originally fell to the Board of Managers, until 1841, when the Society hired an Almoner to investigate cases and provide aid. In addition to the primary fund, special funds were also established for specific charitable purposes, which can be seen in the President's Fund and Scholarship Fund subseries.
  - Subseries II.1: Manager's and Almoner's Record Books, 1802-1979
    The subseries contains ledger volumes that detail individual requests for aid and corresponding disbursements made by the Society. The volumes are in chronological order.
    Conditions Governing Access
    By agreement with the donor of the collection, almoners' records are restricted from access for 35 years from the date of the record. Accordingly, as of 2022, all almoners' records from 1987 and later are restricted from access.
    - Manager's Book, 1802 - 1825 (Offsite-box SA-9, Volume 61)
    - Manager's Book, 1825 - 1846 (Offsite-box SA-22, Volume 62)
    - Account of Burials and Record of Hospital Cases, 1890 - 1978 (Offsite-box SA-9, Volume 63)
    - Almoner's Record Book, November 1905 - September 1907 (Offsite-box SA-14, Volume 64)
    - Almoner's Record Book, October 1907 - April 1909 (Offsite-box SA-14, Volume 65)
    - Almoner's Record Book, May 1909 - July 1911 (Offsite-box SA-14, Volume 66)
    - Almoner's Record Book, December 1918 - January 1922 (Offsite-box SA-18, Volume 67)
    - Almoner's Record Book, February 1922 - September 1924 (Offsite-box SA-21, Volume 68)
    - Almoner's Record Book, September 1924 - February 1927 (Offsite-box SA-17, Volume 69)
    - Almoner's Record Book, February 1927 - August 1928 (Offsite-box SA-16, Volume 70)
    - Almoner's Record Book, September 1928 - July 1930 (Offsite-box SA-16, Volume 71)
    - Almoner's Record Book, August 1930 - October 1933 (Offsite-box SA-18, Volume 72)
    - Almoner's Record Book, November 1933 - April 1938 (Offsite-box SA-17, Volume 73)
    - Almoner's Record Book, May 1938 - January 1945 (Offsite-box SA-19, Volume 74)
    - Almoner's Record Book, February 1945 - September 1953 (Offsite-box SA-19, Volume 75)
    - Almoner's Record Book, October 1953 - January 1962 (Offsite-box SA-20, Volume 76)
    - Almoner's Record Book, February 1962 - June 1973 (Offsite-box SA-20, Volume 77)
    - Almoner's Record Book, July 1973 - May 1979 (Offsite-box SA-21, Volume 78)
  - Subseries II.2: Almoner's Reports, 1916-1980
    The reports contain monthly summaries of individual cases overseen by the Almoner. The files are ordered chronologically
    See also the reports contained in the published Annual Reports in Series I.
    - Summary of charitable work, 1916 - 1924 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 1)
    - Summary of charitable work, 1925 - 1931 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 2)
    - Almoner's reports, 1953 - 1959 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 3)
    - Almoner's reports, 1960 - 1963 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 4)
    - Almoner's reports, 1964 - 1967 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 5)
    - Almoner's reports, 1968 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 6)
    - Almoner's reports, 1969 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 7)
    - Almoner's reports, 1970 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 1)
    - Almoner's reports, 1971 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 2)
    - Almoner's reports, 1972 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 3)
    - Almoner's reports, 1973 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 4)
    - Almoner's reports, 1974 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 5)
    - Almoner's reports, 1975 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 6)
    - Almoner's reports, 1976 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 7)
    - Almoner's reports, 1977 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 8)
    - Almoner's reports, 1978 - 1980 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 9)
  - Subseries II.3: Almoner's Case Files, 1939-1991
    The subseries contains files kept by the Almoner related to individual applicants and recipients of aid. Material includes correspondence, applications, and related documentation. The files are arranged alphabetically according the the applicant's name.
    - Allen - Barr, 1978 - 1988 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 1)
    - Beaumont, 1939 -1988 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 2)
    - Bell - Borcherding, 1967 - 1989 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 3)
    - Brown - Cairney, 1978 - 1987 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 4)
    - Calicchio - Campbell, 1983 - 1988 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 5)
    - Coyle, 1969 - 1982 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 6)
    - Ferns - Gillanders, 1986 - 1989 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 7)
    - Grant, 1972 - 1980 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 8)
    - Green - Guthrie, 1983 - 1987 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 9)
    - Halbert - Kerrigan, 1975 - 1988 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 10)
    - Koll - McElroy, 1973 - 1986 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 1)
    - McKechnie, 1950 - 1986 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 2)
    - McKinnon - Mashburn, 1982 - 1988 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 3)
    - Mathie, 1974 - 1988 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 4)
    - Mislin - Reilly, 1980 - 1988 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 5)
    - Roberts, 1969 - 1983 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 6)
    - Robinson - Voege, 1981 - 1989 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 7)
    - Wickstrom - Young, 1982 - 1991 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 8)
  - Subseries II.4: President's Fund, 1944-1989
    The President's Fund was established in 1944 in response to the effects of World War II in Scotland. Separate from the Permanent Fund, which could only be spent in New York, it allowed the Society to supply aid to Scottish charities at the discretion of the President. Records in this subseries consist chiefly of correspondence related to individual donors and recipient organizations. There are also administrative reports on the status of the fund.
    - Correspondence and reports, 1944 - 1947 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1948 - 1950 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1951 - 1954 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1955 - 1956 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1957 - 1958 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1959 - 1960 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1961 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1962 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1963 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1964 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1965; 1969 - 1976 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1982 - 1983 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1984 - 1985 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1986 - 1989 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 5)
  - Subseries II.5: Scholarship Fund, 1955-1992
    The Scholarship Fund (1955 – 1992) was established as part of the Society's Bicentennial celebrations. For the majority of its history, it provided financial aid to Scottish students wishing to study in American universities and vice versa.
    Material in this subseries was filed in two categories prior to processing. The first was a general file containing administrative correspondence, fundraising material, program information, and other records. The second contained correspondence and records related to the individual scholarship recipients. This arrangement is preserved under the headings "Committee records", which is arranged first, and "Student files", which follows. There is, however, some overlap between the two categories. Each set is ordered chronologically.
    - Committee records, 1955 - 1959 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 6)
    - Committee records, 1960 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 7)
    - Committee records, 1961 - 1962 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 8)
    - Committee records, fundraising luncheon, 1962 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 1)
    - Committee records, 1963 - 1969 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 2)
    - Committee records, 1979 - 1982 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 3)
    - Committee records, 1983 - 1984 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 4)
    - Committee records, student reports, 1983 - 1989 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 5)
    - Committee records, 1985 - 1987 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 6)
    - Committee records, 1988 - 1989 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 7)
    - Committee records, 1992 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 8)
    - Student files, 1960 - 1964 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 1)
    - Student files, 1964 - 1966 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 2)
    - Student files, 1965 - 1968 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 3)
    - Student files, 1968 - 1971 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 4)
    - Student files, 1971 - 1975 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 5)
    - Student files, 1975 - 1978 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 6)
    - Student files, 1978 - 1980 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 7)
    - Student files, 1980 - 1981 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 8)
    - Student files, 1981 - 1982 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 9)
    - Student files, 1982 - 1983 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 1)
    - Student files, 1983 - 1984 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 2)
    - Student files, American, 1984 - 1985 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 3)
    - Student files, Scottish, 1984 - 1985 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 4)
    - Student files, American, 1985 - 1986 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 5)
    - Student files, Scottish, 1985 - 1986 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 6)
    - Student files, American, 1986 - 1987 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 7)
    - Student files, Scottish, 1986 - 1987 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 1)
    - Student files, American, 1987 - 1988 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 2)
    - Student files, Scottish, 1987 - 1988 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 3)
    - Student files, American, 1988 - 1989 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 4)
    - Student files, Scottish, 1988 - 1989 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 5)
- Series III: Membership Records (RESTRICTIONS APPLY), circa 1820-2000s
  Membership records contain information about the individuals who have belonged to the Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York.
  The series consists of the following subseries: Registers, Member Applications, "Archived" Member Files spanning the period from the 1850s to the 2000s, and "Unarchived" Member Files, spanning the period from the 1850s to the 1980s. The archived and unarchived member files reflect the arrangement of the material at the time of accession. Archived files are foldered, and unarchived files are housed in original envelopes.
  By agreement with the donor of the collection, member records are restricted from access for 35 years from the date of the record. Accordingly, as of 2022, all member records from 1987 and later are restricted from access.
  - Subseries III.1: Registers, circa 1820-1987
    Bound volumes are arranged first, followed by foldered material. Within the bound volumes, manuscript material is first, followed by typescripts, and then printed matter. Apart from those considerations, items are ordered chronologically according to their date of creation.
    The subseries contains historical lists of members compiled mostly during the early 20th century.
    - List of members, 1785 - 1820, undated, circa 1820 (Offsite-box SA-8, Volume 79)
    - Roll of members, volume 1, 1756 - 1906 (Offsite-box SA-15, Volume 80)
    - Roll of members, volume 2, 1906 - 1960, circa 1906 - 1960 (Offsite-box SA-15, Volume 81)
    - Roll of members, volume 3, 1960 - 1987, circa 1960 - 1987 (Offsite-box SA-15, Volume 82)
    - Typescript roll of members from 1756 to 1910, undated, circa 1910 (Offsite-box SA-8, Volume 83)
    - Typescript biographical register, volume 2, part 1, 1807 - 1831, circa 1920s (Offsite-box SA-8, Volume 84)
    - Typescript biographical register, volume 2, part 2, 1832 - 1856, circa 1920s (Offsite-box SA-8, Volume 85)
    - Typescript biographical register, 1857 - 1906, volume 1, circa 1920 - 1930 (Offsite-box SA-9, Volume 86)
    - Typescript biographical register, 1857 - 1906, volume 2, circa 1920 - 1930 (Offsite-box SA-9, Volume 87)
    - Typescript biographical register, 1857 - 1906, volume 3, circa 1920 - 1930 (Offsite-box SA-9, Volume 88)
    - Typescript register, 1907 - 1919, circa 1920 - 1930 (Offsite-box SA-9, Volume 89)
    - Roster of Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York with Biographical. Part I...1756 - 1783, 1911 (Offsite-box SA-9, Volume 90)